Register of the Bernard Gotfryd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Bernard Gotfryd papers
1940-2008
2008C24
Hoover Institution Archives
9 manuscript boxes (3.6 linear feet)
The Bernard Gotfryd papers reflect Gotfryd's status as both an author of true stories about the Holocaust and a professional photographer. The papers consist of clippings, correspondence, and numerous photographs and include hundreds of letters of appreciation from students and teachers of classes that Gotfryd spoke to about his experiences as a Holocaust survivor.
Gotfryd, Bernard, 1924-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Bernard Gotfryd was a Holocaust survivor and celebrated staff photographer for Newsweek for more than three decades until his retirement in the late 1980s.
Bernard Gotfryd was born in 1924, in Radom, Poland, to Jewish parents. During World War II, he worked as an apprentice photographer at a photo studio in the Radom ghetto. His involvement with the Polish underground led to his imprisonment in a concentration camp. He spent time in six concentration camps before his liberation from Gusen II in May 1945. Two years later he immigrated to the United States. After several years of service with the U.S. Army Signal Corps, in 1957 Gotfryd became a photojournalist for Newsweek. During his thirty years with the magazine, he took portraits of many of the most influential and important people of the day--statesmen, politicians, writers, musicians, painters--as well as those of many other, less prominent individuals.
After his retirement, Gotfryd turned to writing and lecturing. His extraordinary wartime reminiscences were published as some thirty autobiographical short stories under the title Anton the Dove Fancier. He lectured extensively about the Holocaust, particularly to high school students in the New York City area. Several hundred letters from grateful listeners, included in his papers, bear witness to the effectiveness of his presentations. Gotfryd died in 2016.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Bernard Gotfryd papers reflect Gotfryd's status as both an author of true stories about the Holocaust and a professional photographer. The papers consist of clippings, correspondence, and numerous photographs. The correspondence series includes hundreds of letters of appreciation from students and teachers of classes that Gotfryd spoke to about his experiences as a Holocaust survivor. These letters show how moved Gotfryd's audiences were by his talks. The correspondence also contains readers' reactions to Anton the Dove Fancier, the compilation of Gotfryd's stories about the Holocaust and his youth in Poland.
The photographs in the collection cover the range of Gotfryd's work for Newsweek magazine: the prints depict politicians, writers, and artists. In almost all cases, the subjects of the photographs are identified.
Related Collection
A more extensive collection of Bernard Gotfryd's photographs are located at the Library of Congress. See http://www.loc.gov/pictures/item/2010650142/
World politics--Pictorial works.
- Biographical File, 1945-2006
  - Announcements, 1972-2000 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Biographies, 1986-2006 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Certificates, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Citation, 1991 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Clippings, 1952-2006 (Box-folder 1: 5-9)
  - Identification card, 1945 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Interview, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1950 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Military service records, 1948-1952 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Programs, 1985-2001 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Serial issues, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Testimonials, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 1: 16)
- Correspondence, 1948-2008
  - General, 1964-2008
    - A, 1965-1999 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - B, 1964-1991 (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - C, 1975-2003 (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - D, 1965-1988 (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - E, 1967-2002 (Box-folder 1: 21)
    - F, 1967-2005 (Box-folder 1: 22)
    - G, 1965-1991 (Box-folder 1: 23)
    - H, 1968-1991 (Box-folder 1: 24)
    - I, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 1: 25)
    - J, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 26)
    - K, 1969-2000 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - L, 1967-2003 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - M, 1971-1998 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - N, 1970-1998 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - P, 1967-2006 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - R, 1969-1998 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - S, 1968-2000 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - T, 1967-2008 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - U, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - V, 1967-1998 (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - W, 1968-2000 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - Y, 1978-1992 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Z, 1996 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Students and teachers, 1985-2008
    - 1985 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 2: 16-17)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 2: 18)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 2: 19-22)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 3: 3-4)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 3: 5-7)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 3: 8-9)
    - 2002 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - 2002 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - 2003 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - 2004 (Box-folder 4: 3-4)
    - 2005 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - 2006 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - 2007-2008 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Unidentified, 1948-2005 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Abé, K., 1988 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Abreu, Hector, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Adelson, Alan, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Andre Deutsch Ltd. (Esther Whitby), 1990-1992 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Billings, Harold, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Bokser, Ben Zion, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Brustein, Robert, 1980 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1974 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1970 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - A Campaign to Remember, 1988 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Clemens, Anik, 1999 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Clubb, O. Edmund, 1971 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Cochran, Pam, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Community Gallery of the Brooklyn Museum (Henri Ghent, Richard Waller), 1972 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Dahlberg, Edward, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - De Vries, Peter, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - DeFanti, Charles, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Distel, Barbara, 2001 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Doctorow, E. L., 1996 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Duboys, Tibbi, 1998 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Eisenhower, Julie Nixon, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Elliott, Osborn, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Eshaghian, 2000-2005 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Evans, Allan, 1987 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Fast, Howard, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Feinberg, Kevin, 2005 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Fine, Susan, 2000 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Fischer, Tanja, 2001 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Forest Hills High School (Alyce Barnett, Rowena Karsh, June l. Schwarz), 1996-2003 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Fox, Jeannie, 2003 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Frazier, Ian, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Goldwyn, Judy, 1992 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Haien, Jeannette, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - Hercules, Frank E. M., 1968-1988 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Herman, Michelle, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Holmes, John Clellon, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Hotai, Kazumi, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Howe, Irving, 1985 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Isaacs, Stephen D., 1984-1985 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Jhabvala, Ruth Prawer, 1985 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Judell, Debra T., 1983 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Julian Bach Literary Agency, Inc., 1991 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - Karski, Jan, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Keenan, Paul, 1994 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - Knaths, Karl, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - Kuperstein, Isaiah, 1988 (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - Levi, Lucia, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Levi, Primo, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 34)
  - Levin, Ira, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 5: 35)
  - Lewis, Claude, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 5: 36)
  - Lockhart, Patricia, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 37)
  - Lucioli, Luigi Elvio, 2001 (Box-folder 5: 38)
  - Ludlum, Robert, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 5: 39)
  - MacKenzie, Rachel, 1971 (Box-folder 5: 40)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1968-1994 (Box-folder 5: 41)
  - Makowski, Roger Jan, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 42)
  - Mann, Nancy, 1994 (Box-folder 5: 43)
  - Maysles Films, Inc., 1995 (Box-folder 5: 44)
  - McCabe, Gibson, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 45)
  - Midstream, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 5: 46)
  - Morris, Hobie, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 5: 47)
  - Morrison, Toni, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 5: 48)
  - Munro, Eleanor, 1989-2003 (Box-folder 5: 49)
  - Museum of Jewish Heritage (Elizabeth Edelstein, David G. Maxwell, Paul Radensky), 2004-2006 (Box-folder 5: 50)
  - O'Donnell, Edward J., 1991 (Box-folder 5: 51)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 52)
  - Photographers East (Ellen M. Dooley), 2002 (Box-folder 5: 53)
  - Rea, Andrew, 2003 (Box-folder 5: 54)
  - Redmond, John and Nina, 2005 (Box-folder 5: 55)
  - Reed, Robert, 1985 (Box-folder 5: 56)
  - Rosenberg, Richard, 1971 (Box-folder 5: 57)
  - Rosenman, Jane, 1985 (Box-folder 5: 58)
  - Sacco, Mary Anne, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 59)
  - Sacks, Oliver W., 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5: 60)
  - Schimmenti, Virginia, 2000 (Box-folder 5: 61)
  - Schneider, Iris, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 62)
  - Scrase, David, 1999-2005 (Box-folder 5: 63)
  - Sedota, David, 2000 (Box-folder 5: 64)
  - Seligmann, Jean, 1990 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Shapiro, Karen, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Shapiro, Sidney, 2000 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Shawn, Karen, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Sillau, Robin, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Simmons, Charles, 1987 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Slavitt, David, 1965-1986 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Smiley, Maya, 2000 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Smith, Mary-Anne Trone, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Spaeth, Brian, 2005 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Spielberg, Steven, 2004 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Stanley, Brenda, 1991 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Stoppard, Tom, 1984 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Styron, William, 1967-2003 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Suzuki, Hidesuke, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Tannenbaum, Paul, 2001 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Teplitsky, Lynn, 1991 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Trenkner, Joachim, 1967-1982 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Ullmann, Liv, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - United States Information Service, undated (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Voinovitch, Irina and Vladimir, 1987-2001 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Vonnegut, Kurt, Jr., 1968-1983 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Walsh, Thomas deWitt, 1983 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Watson, Robert, 1968-2003 (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Weatherspoon Art Gallery (James E. Tucker), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Weinberg, Harvey, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Weinstein, Rebecca, 1999 (Box-folder 6: 27)
  - Whittaker, Ted, 1971 (Box-folder 6: 28)
  - Wiesel, Elie, 1985 (Box-folder 6: 29)
  - Williams, Jonathan, 1969 (Box-folder 6: 30)
  - Wolfe, Tom, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 31)
  - Wolff, Jurgen, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - Wolpe, Gerald I., 1998 (Box-folder 6: 33)
  - Woodward, Ken, 2006 (Box-folder 6: 34)
  - Wright, Penelope, 2002 (Box-folder 6: 35)
  - Youdovin, Ira S., 1992 (Box-folder 6: 36)
  - Zabner, Jacob, 1976-1986 (Box-folder 6: 37)
- Speeches and Writings, 1970-2004
  - Review of book on ballet, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 38)
  - "Three Eggs,", 1990 (Box-folder 6: 39)
  - "Behind the Wall,", 1990 October 5 (Box-folder 6: 40)
  - "On a Rainy Night,", 1991 January 18 (Box-folder 6: 41)
  - "Stolarz Izaak,", 1996 (Box-folder 6: 42)
  - "Za Murem,", 1998 (Box-folder 6: 43)
  - "My Salzburg Journey: Mauthausen Revisited,", 2000 June (Box-folder 6: 44)
  - "My Journey to Dachau,", 2002 (Box-folder 6: 45)
  - Untitled poem, 2004 (Box-folder 6: 46)
- Subject File, 1978-2001
  - Bach, Julian, 1978 (Box-folder 6: 47)
  - Gusen concentration camp, 2000 (Box-folder 6: 48)
  - International Youth Meeting in Dachau, 2001 (Box-folder 6: 49)
- Photographs, 1940-2000
  - Taken by Bernard Gotfryd, 1960-1991
    - Tearsheets, 1965-1987 (Box-folder 6: 50)
      Scope and Contents note
      Pages from Newsweek containing photographs by Gotfryd.
    - Black and white prints, 1960-1991
      - Abe, Kōbō, 1987 (Box-folder 7: 1)
      - Allen, Woody, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 2)
      - Anderson, John, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 3)
      - Appelfeld, Aharon, 1991 (Box-folder 7: 4)
      - Auden, W. H., 1970 (Box-folder 7: 5)
      - Baez, Joan, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 6)
      - Balanchine, George, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 7)
      - Barth, John, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 8)
      - Batcha, Robert, 1988 (Box-folder 7: 9)
      - Beaton, Cecil, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 10)
      - Bellow, Saul, 1965 (Box-folder 7: 11)
      - Benchley, Peter, 1976 (Box-folder 7: 12)
      - Berlin, Irving, 1962 (Box-folder 7: 13)
      - Bing, Rudolf, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 14)
      - Bogdanovich, Peter, 1972 (Box-folder 7: 15)
      - Brokaw, Tom, 1982 (Box-folder 7: 16)
      - Brandon, Marlon, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 17)
      - Bronfman, Edgar, 1963 (Box-folder 7: 18)
      - Brustein, Robert, 1972 (Box-folder 7: 19)
      - Carter, Jimmy, 1977 (Box-folder 7: 20)
      - Carter, Rosalynn and Joan Mondale, 1976 (Box-folder 7: 21)
      - Casals, Pablo, 1960 (Box-folder 7: 22)
      - Cassill, R. V., 1990 (Box-folder 7: 23)
      - Castro, Fidel, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 24)
      - Cheever, John, 1976 (Box-folder 7: 25)
      - Chirico, Giorgio de, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 26)
      - Clifford, John, 1971 (Box-folder 7: 27)
      - Coltrane, John, 1964 (Box-folder 7: 28)
      - Condon, Richard, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 29)
      - Conroy, Frank, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 30)
      - Dahlberg, Edward, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 7: 31)
      - Davies, Robertson, 1972 (Box-folder 7: 32)
      - De Lillo, Don, 1987 (Box-folder 7: 33)
      - De Vries, Peter, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 7: 34)
      - Delorean, John, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 35)
      - Disch, Thomas, 1985 (Box-folder 7: 36)
      - Doctorow, E. L., 1970 (Box-folder 7: 37)
      - Dunaway, Faye, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 38)
      - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1970 (Box-folder 7: 39)
      - Fielder, Leslie, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 40)
      - Ford, Henry and Cristina, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 41)
      - Ginnever, Charles, 1968 (Box-folder 7: 42)
      - Ginzburg, Ralph, 1970-1987 (Box-folder 7: 43)
      - Graham, Billy, 1972 (Box-folder 7: 44)
      - Grass, Günter, 1972 (Box-folder 7: 45)
      - Greenspan, Alan, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 46)
      - Gregory, Dick, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 47)
      - Gross, Chaim, 1976 (Box-folder 7: 48)
      - Hazzard, Shirley, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 49)
      - Heller, Joseph, 1965 (Box-folder 7: 50)
      - Hellman, Lillian, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 51)
      - Heschel, Abraham, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 52)
      - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1965 (Box-folder 7: 53)
      - Humphrey, Hubert, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 7: 54)
      - Hunter, Charlayne, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 55)
      - Hurt, Mississippi John, 1965 (Box-folder 7: 56)
      - Hutton, Lauren, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 57)
      - Jackson, Henry, 1972 (Box-folder 7: 58)
      - Janeway, Elizabeth, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 59)
      - Jhabvala, Ruth Prawer, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 60)
      - Johnson, Philip, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 61)
      - Jones, James Earl, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 7: 62)
      - Kanin, Garson, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 63)
      - Jong, Erica and Howard Fast, 1976 (Box-folder 7: 64)
      - Kaplan, Johanna, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 65)
      - Kennedy, Robert F., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7: 66)
      - Kennedy, William, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 67)
      - Kertesz, André, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 68)
      - Kitman, Marvin, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 69)
      - Kligman, Ruth, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 70)
      - Kline, Kevin, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 71)
      - Knaths, Karl, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 1)
      - Kokoschka, Oskar, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 2)
      - Kosinski, Jerzy, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 3)
      - Krasner, Lee, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 4)
      - Laughlin, Clarence John, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 5)
      - Leary, Timothy and Richard Alpert, 1963 (Box-folder 8: 6)
      - Lerner, Jay, 1974 (Box-folder 8: 7)
      - Levin, Ira, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 8)
      - Levin, Mayer, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 9)
      - Lifton, Betty, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 10)
      - Lifton, Robert Jay, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 11)
      - Lind, Yakov, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 8: 12)
      - Lindsay, John, 1964 (Box-folder 8: 13)
      - Loren, Sophia, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 14)
      - Ludlum, Robert, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 15)
      - MacLaine, Shirley, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 16)
      - Mailer, Norman, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 8: 17)
      - Marchi, John, 1969 (Box-folder 8: 18)
      - Margaret, Princess, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 19)
      - Matthiessen, Peter, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 20)
      - Maxwell, William, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 21)
      - McCarthy, Eugene, 1968 (Box-folder 8: 22)
      - McClintock, Barbara, 1983 (Box-folder 8: 23)
      - McCluhan, Marshall, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 8: 24)
      - Merman, Ethel and David Merrick, 1963 (Box-folder 8: 25)
      - Merwin, W. S., 1970 (Box-folder 8: 26)
      - Meyner, Robert, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 27)
      - Monk, Thelonius, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 28)
      - Moore, Marianne, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 29)
      - Morrison, Toni, 1982 (Box-folder 8: 30)
      - Mostel, Zero, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 31)
      - Muskie, Edmund, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 32)
      - Newman, Barnet, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 33)
      - Nixon, Richard M., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 8: 34)
      - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 35)
      - O'Dwyer, Paul, 1968 (Box-folder 8: 36)
      - O'Keefe, Georgia, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 37)
      - Oz, Amos, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 38)
      - Paltrow, Lynn, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 39)
      - Papp, Joe, 1977 (Box-folder 8: 40)
      - Perelman, S. J., 1970 (Box-folder 8: 41)
      - Plisetskaya, Maya, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 42)
      - Puzo, Mario, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 43)
      - Rauschenberg, Robert, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 44)
      - Rivers, Larry, 1968 (Box-folder 8: 45)
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D., Jr., 1966 (Box-folder 8: 46)
      - Sacks, Oliver, 1983 (Box-folder 8: 47)
      - Shoumatoff, Alex, 1979 (Box-folder 8: 48)
      - Sheed, Wilfrid, 1970-1987 (Box-folder 8: 49)
      - Shrimpton, Jean, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 50)
      - Simon, Sidney, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 51)
      - Singer, Isaac Bashevis, 1976 (Box-folder 8: 52)
      - Smith, Eugene, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 53)
      - Stafford, Jean, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 54)
      - Steig, Jeremy, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 55)
      - Steinem, Gloria, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 56)
      - Stevenson, Adlai, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 57)
      - Streisand, Barbra, 1973 (Box-folder 8: 58)
      - Thorp, Roderick, 1966 (Box-folder 8: 59)
      - Torez, Tereska, 1968 (Box-folder 8: 60)
      - Trilling, Lionel, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 61)
      - Turbeville, Deborah, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 62)
      - Twiggy, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 63)
      - Ullmann, Liv, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 64)
      - Vargas Llosa, Mario, 1987 (Box-folder 8: 65)
      - Van Peebles, Melvin, 1968 (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - Velikovsky, Immanuel, 1968 (Box-folder 9: 2)
      - Verdon, Gwen and Ray Walston, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 3)
      - Voinovich, Vladimir, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 4)
      - Vonnegut, Kurt, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 9: 5)
      - Voznesensky, Andrei and Allen Ginsberg, 1965 (Box-folder 9: 6)
      - Wagner, Robert, 1963 (Box-folder 9: 7)
      - Wainwright, Loudon, undated (Box-folder 9: 8)
      - Warhol, Andy, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 9)
      - Westlake, Donald E., 1983 (Box-folder 9: 10)
      - Wiesel, Elie, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 11)
      - Wiseman, Fred, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 12)
      - Wodehouse, P. G., 1965 (Box-folder 9: 13)
      - Zeckendorf, William, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - Taken by others, 1940-2000
    - Depicting Bernard Gotfryd, 1940-1978 (Box-folder 9: 15)
    - Depicting students with art projects, 2000 (Box-folder 9: 16)